Register of the Alfred Kohlberg papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Alfred Kohlberg papers
1937-2005
61002
Hoover Institution Archives
232 manuscript boxes, 5 card file boxes, 3 oversize boxes 102.6 linear feet
Correspondence, memoirs and other writings, newsletters, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and sound recordings relating to communism in the United States, China, and other parts of Asia, and to anti-communist movements in the United States.
Kohlberg, Alfred, 1887-1960.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1961, with increments received in subsequent years.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1887 Born, San Francisco, California
1908 B.A., University of California
1916-1960 Textile importer dealing in Nationalist Chinese goods
1916-1960 Member of Board, Institute of Pacific Relations
1916-1960 Chairman, American Jewish League Against Communism
1916-1960 Chairman, American China Policy Association
1960 April 7 Died, New York City
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, memoirs and other writings, newsletters, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and sound recordings relating to communism in the United States, China, and other parts of Asia, and to anti-communist movements in the United States.
American China Policy Association.; American Jewish League against Communism.; Institute of Pacific Relations.; Anti-communist movements--United States.; Communism--Asia.; Communism--China.; Communism--United States.; Subversive activities--United States.
- Correspondence and Subject File, 1944-1960 (Boxes 1-207)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, newsletters, clippings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by name of subject or correspondent.
  - A, miscellaneous
    - 1958-1959 (Box 1)
    - 1957
    - 1956
    - 1955
    - 1954
    - 1953
    - 1952
    - 1951
    - 1950, 2 folders
    - 1949, 2 folders
    - 1948
    - 1947
    - 1946
  - Abraham Lincoln National Republican Club
  - Academic freedom
  - Acheson, Dean
    - 1952-1960
    - 1946-1951, 8 folders (Box 2)
    - 1945-1952
    - Reports, drafts, background material, undated; 2 folders
  - Adams, John Quincey (Box 3)
  - Adams, Josephine Truslow
  - Adams, Phelps
  - Adams, Sherman
  - Adler, Selig
  - Adler, Solomon
  - Aetna Life Insurance Company
  - Africa
  - Agee, James
  - Agricultural Missions, Inc.
  - Agronsky, Martin
  - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, Inc.
  - Air Force
  - Alden, Robert
  - Aldrich, Winthrop W.
  - Alert
  - Alexander, Holmes
  - Alexander, Robert J.
  - Alexander, Ruth, 3 folders
  - Algeria
  - All American Conference to Combat Communism
    - 1954-1959, 4 folders
    - 1950-1953, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Allen, Douglas H.
  - Allen, Edward W.
  - Allen, George V.
  - Allen, Raymond B.
  - Allen, Robert S., 2 folders
  - Allen-Bradley Company
  - Allison, John W.
  - Allman, Norwood F., 2 folders
  - Alsop, Joseph and Stewart, 1941-1959; 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Altschul, Frank
  - Amerasia
  - America
  - America Speaks
    - Sound recording of WOR-TV, 10:30 PM, 1953 August 15
      Access
      Use copy reference number: 61002.8
    - Rest of folder not yet described
  - American Academy of Asian Studies
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science (Box 6)
  - American Arbitration Association
  - American-Asian Educational Exchange, Inc.
  - American Asiatic Association
  - American Assembly, 3 folders
  - American Association for the United Nations, Inc., 2 folders
  - American Bar Association
  - American Broadcasting Company
  - American Christian Alliance (Box 7)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 2 folders
  - American Coalition
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born
  - American Council of Christian Laymen
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 2 folders
  - American Federation of Labor, 2 folders
  - American Flag Committee, 1954-1957
  - American Forum of the Air
  - American Forum for Socialist Education
  - American Foundation for Political Education
  - American Friends of the Captive Nations
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box 8)
  - American Friends of Russian Freedom
  - American Korean Foundation
  - American Legion
    - 1952-1959, 8 folders
    - Karl Baarslag, 1947-1952; 5 folders (Box 9)
    - 1948-1949
  - American Legion Magazine
    - 1956-1958
    - 1947-1955, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - American Magazine
  - American Medical Association
  - American Mercury, 2 folders
  - American Nationalist, Frank L. Britton, editor
  - American President Lines
  - American Russian Institute, 2 folders
  - American Security Council
  - American Telephone and Telegraph Company
  - American Veterans' Committee
  - American World Intelligence, Christopher S. Norborg, editor, 1947-1950
  - American Youth for Democracy
  - American Youth for a Free World
  - Americans for Constitutional Action
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 2 folders
  - Ammunition (dumped in India at the end of World War II) (Box 11)
  - Amory, Robert
  - Amoss, Ulius L., editor of Inform, 4 folders
  - Andelson, Robert Vernon
  - Answers for Americans
  - Anti-Bolshevik block of nations
  - Anti-intellectual
  - Anti-slavery
  - Antonini, Luigi
  - Appleby, Paul H. (Box 12)
  - Arens, Richard [See also: Un-American Activities Committee]
  - Argonaut
  - Armed Forces talk
  - Arms of Friendship
  - Armstrong, O. K.
  - Army, Department of the, 2 folders
  - Army Intelligence Service, U.S.
  - Arnold, Benedict
  - Arnold, Julean, 2 folders
  - Aron, Raymond
  - Art
  - Articles by Alfred Kohlberg
  - Ashland, Wisconsin Daily Press, John Chapple, editor
  - Ascoli, Max
  - Asia
  - Asia Magazine
  - Asia and the Americas
  - Asia Book Club
  - Asia Foundation
  - Asia Institute
  - Asia Society
  - Asian-Afro Conference held in Cairo, 1957 December
  - Asian Peoples Anti-Communist League, 2 folders
  - Asian Peoples Anti-Communist League (Box 13)
  - Asian Recorder
  - Assembly of Captive European Nations
  - Associated Industries of Missouri
  - Associated Press
  - Association for Asian Studies
  - Association of American Physicians and Surgeons
  - Atkinson, Brooks
  - Atkinson, Henry A.
  - Atlantic Charter
  - Atlantic Congress, 1959 June 5-9
  - Atlantic Monthly
  - Atlantic Pact
  - Atlantic Union
  - Atomic energy
  - Atomic Energy Commission
  - Atomic Scientists Bulletin
  - Atrocities
  - Attlee, Clement R.
  - Attorney General's list of subversives
  - Aufbau
  - Austria
  - Author Meets the Critics, 2 folders
    - Sound recording, 1952 April 24; 1 disc
      Use copy reference number: 61002.4
    - Rest of folder not yet described
  - Authors (Box 14)
  - AWARE, Inc.
  - B, miscellaneous
    - 1959
    - 1958
    - 1957 July-December
    - 1957 January-June
    - 1956 July-December
    - 1956 January-June
    - 1955 January-June
    - 1954 January-June
    - 1953 July-December
    - 1953 January-June
    - 1952
    - 1951
    - 1950
    - 1949 (Box 15)
    - 1948
    - 1947
    - 1946
    - 1945
    - *, 1945-1949
    - *, 1950-1951
  - Baarslag, Karl, 2 folders
  - Babsons Report
  - Bailey, Gerald
  - Baker, Tom
  - Baldwin, Hanson W., 2 folders
  - Baldwin, Roger
  - Ball, Joseph H., 2 folders
  - Ball, Lee H.
  - Ball, Lucille
  - Baltimore meeting, 1954 March 16
  - Baltimore meeting, 1951 July 16
  - Baltimore Sun
  - Bandung conference
  - Bang-Jensen, Povl
  - Barger, Harry S.
  - Barkley, Alben
  - Barmine, Alexander
  - Barnard, Chester I.
  - Barnes, Joseph (Box 16)
  - Barnett, A. Doak
  - Barnett, Frank, 2 folders
  - Barnett, Robert W.
  - Barr, Stringfellow
  - Barrett, Edward
  - Barrett, Robert
  - Barron, Bryton
  - Barth, Alan
  - Barton, Bruce
  - Baruch, Bernard, 2 folders
  - Baxter International Economic Research Bureau
  - Beall, Jack
  - Beasley, Norman
  - Beaty, John Owen
  - Beauvoir, Simone de
  - Beaverbrook, Lord
  - Belden, Mary Addams
  - Bell, Don
  - Bell, Elliott V.
  - Beltran, Pedro G.
  - Benson, Secretary (Ezra Taft Benson)
  - Bentley, Alvin M.
  - Bentley, Elizabeth
  - Benton, William
  - Beria, Lavrentii
  - Berkner, Lloyd V.
  - Berle, Adolph A., Jr.
  - Berlin
  - Bernays, Edward L.
  - Berstein, David
  - Berrier, Hilaire du
  - Bertolette, Calvin M. (Box 17)
  - Bess, Demaree, 2 folders
  - Bethune, Mary
  - Bevan, Aneurin
  - Bevin, Ernest
  - Bibliography
  - Bialer, Seweryn
  - Bidien, Charles
  - Billington, Ray Allen
  - "Bind Wounds or Prevent Them," Kohlberg speech, 1957 April 25
  - Birch Society. The John Birch Society
  - Birkhead, L. M., Friends of Democracy, 2 folders
  - Birth control
  - Bishop, Jim
  - Bishop's letter
  - Bisson, T. A.
  - Bissonette, Georges
  - Black, Hugo
  - Blatnik, John
  - Blueprint letters ( Blueprint for World Conquest ), 2 folders
  - Bluden, Godfrey
  - B'nai B'rith
  - B'nai B'rith Messenger
  - Bodde, Derk
  - Boddy, Manchester, 2 folders
  - Bohlen, Charles E. (Box 18)
  - Bohlinger, Alfred J., 2 folders
  - Bolivia
  - Bolles, Blair
  - Bonbrake, Mrs. A. E.
  - Book ( Let the Chinese Communists Speak for Themselves. A digest of China's New Democracy, by Mao Tse-tung)
  - Bookburning
  - Book Find Club
  - Book of the Month Club
  - Book reviews
  - Bookmailer
  - Books to buy
  - Boorman, Howard L.
  - Borton, Hugh
  - Boston Herald
  - Bouscaren, Anthony T.
  - Bowles, Chester, 3 folders
  - Bozell, L. Brent
  - Bozeman, Adda Bruemmer
  - Brada, George
  - Braden, Spruille
  - Bradlee, Benjamin
  - Bradley, Harry L.
  - Brady, John P.
  - Brainin, Joseph
  - Brandeis University
  - Braun, Leopold, 2 folders
  - Brewster, Owen, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Bricker, John W.
  - Bricker amendment
  - Bridges, Harry
  - Bridges, Styles
    - 1947-1959, 13 folders
    - 1947 (Box 20)
  - Brier, Royce
  - British Broadcasting Company
  - British Embassy
  - Broadcasts, 3 folders
  - Bromfield, Louis
  - Bronk, Detlev W.
  - Brookings Institution
  - Brooklyn College communists
  - Browder, Earl, 2 folders
  - Brown, Constantine and Mrs. Brown (Elizabeth Churchill Brown), 2 folders
  - Brown, Peter Campbell
  - Brownell, Herbert, 3 folders
  - Brunauer, Esther Caukin (Box 21)
  - Brussels
  - Bryan, Julien
  - Bryan, Robert T., Jr.
  - Buck, Pearl S., 2 folders
  - Buckley, William, Jr.
  - Budenz, Louis, 5 folders
  - Buffett, Howard, 2 folders
  - Bulgaria
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists
  - Bullitt, William C., 2 folders
  - Bunche, Ralph J., 2 folders
  - Bundy, Harvey Hollister
  - Bundy, William P.
  - Burgess (Guy) and Maclean (Donald)
  - Burma
  - Burnham, James, 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Burton, H. Ralph
  - Busbey, Fred E., 2 folders
  - Business Week
  - Butler, John Marshall
  - Butler, John C.
  - Butterworth, W. Walton
  - Byfield, Robert S.
  - Byrd, Harry F.
  - Byrd, Robert C.
  - Byrnes, James F., 2 folders
  - C, miscellaneous
    - 1959
    - 1958
    - 1957
    - 1956
    - 1955
    - 1954 (Box 23)
    - 1953
    - 1952
    - 1951
    - 1950
    - 1949
    - 1948
    - 1947
    - 1946
    - 1945-1949
    - 1950-1951
  - Cabeen, David Clark
  - Cabot, John Moors
  - Cabot, Thomas T.
  - Cahn, Julius N.
  - Caidin, Martin
  - Cain, Harry P., 3 folders
  - Cairo, Declaration of, 1943 December 1 (Box 24)
  - Calder, A. Bland
  - Caldwell, John C.
  - California, University of
  - Cambodia
  - Canada
  - Canadian Broadcasting Company (Couchiching conference)
  - Canadian Far Eastern Newsletter
  - Canadian Intelligence Service publication
  - Canadian spy exposé [see: Gouzenko]
  - Candour, The British Views-Letter, 2 folders
  - Cannon, Walter B.
  - Canton seminar
  - Canwell, Albert, 2 folders
  - Captive nations
  - Carlson, Evans F., 3 folders
  - Carlson, Oliver
  - Carnegie Corporation
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
  - Carroll, Louis D.
  - Carter, Edward C.
  - Cartridges (Box 25)
  - Cartwright, Frank T.
  - Case, Clifford
  - Case, Everett
  - Castle, Eugene W.
  - Castro, Fidel
  - Cavallaro, Joseph B.
  - CBS (Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.)
  - Celler, Emanual
  - CENIS (Center for International Studies), 5 folders
  - CENIS background material (Box 26)
  - Census
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 3 folders
  - Central News Agency of China
  - Chamber of Commerce of the U.S., 3 folders
  - Chamberlain, John
  - Chamberlin, Neville
  - Chambers, Whittaker
  - Chang, C. M.
  - Chang, P. C.
  - Chaplin, Charlie
  - Chapman, Emanuel
  - Chase National Bank
  - Chase, Stuart
  - Chase, William C.
  - Chemical Bank and Trust Company
  - Chen, Cheng
  - Chen, Chih-mai, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Chen, Li-fu, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Chen, Percy
  - Chen, Theodore Hsi-en
  - Chen, Walter Hanming
  - Chen, Yi, 2 folders
  - Cheney, Ward
  - Chennault, Claire L., 2 folders
  - Cherne, Leo
  - Cherny, Sylvia
  - Chi, Chao-ting
  - Chiang, Ching-kuo
  - Chaing, Kai-shek, Madame and Generalissimo, 3 folders
  - Chiang, Major General Wego
  - Chicago newspaper clippings, 3 folders
  - Chicago, University of (Box 29)
  - Ch'ien, Tuan-sheng, confession of
  - Childs, Marquis
  - China
  - China, aid to (U.S. government), 2 folders
  - China America Council of Commerce and Industry
  - China Club of Seattle, 3 folders
  - China Emergency Committee
  - China famine
  - China Information Bulletin
  - China Institute, correspondence and bulletin
  - China Lobby, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - China Medical Board of New York, Inc.
  - China Monthly, Father Mark Tsai, editor, 2 folders
  - China, Nationalist
  - China planks (national political party platforms), 1952
  - China Today
  - China Weekly Review (later, China Monthly Review)
  - China Welfare Appeal, Inc.
  - China's New Democracy
  - Chinese art exhibit
  - Chinese Association for the United Nations Newsletter (Taiwan), 2 folders
  - Chinese Association for the United Nations Newsletter, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Chinese civil war
  - Chinese communists, 2 folders
  - Chinese communists and Moscow
  - Chinese Consulate General
  - Chinese delegation to the United Nations, 1951-1958; 6 folders
  - Chinese delegation to the United Nations (Box 32)
    4 folders. Includes statements by Dir. Tingfu F. Tsiang.
  - Chinese Democratic League
  - Chinese Embassy
  - Chinese facts and figures
  - Chinese government
  - Chinese mind
  - Chinese Ministry of Information, 2 folders
  - Chinese News Service, Mr. N. C. Nyi, 5 folders
  - Chinese News Service, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Chinese POWs
  - Chinese Press Survey, 1948 November 11
  - Chinese Public Opinion
  - Chinese-Russian Treaty, 1946
  - Chinese scholars
  - Chinese union studies
  - Chodorov, Frank
  - Chou, En-lai, 2 folders
  - Christian Anti-Communism Crusade [See also: Fred Schwartz]
  - Christian Century
  - Christian church in China
  - Christian colleges in China
  - Christian Freedom Foundation, Inc., Howard E. Kershner
  - Christian Herald
  - Christian Science Monitor, 4 folders
  - Christian Science Monitor, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Christianform
  - Christophers, The
  - Chrysler Corporation
  - Chu, Teh
  - Church League of America
  - Church Peace Union
  - Churchill, Winston
  - Churchman, The
  - Cinema Education Guild, Inc.
  - CIO (Congress of Industrial Organizations)
  - Cited organizations and publications
  - Citizens for Taft Committee, 1952 (Box 35)
  - Citizens Foreign Aid Committee
  - Citizens Union
  - Civil Defense Research Associates, Inc.
  - Civil Rights (bill)
  - Civil Rights Congress
  - CLARA (Communist Liberated Area Relief Administration)
  - Clardy, Kit F.
  - Clark, Joseph
  - Clark, General Mark, 2 folders
  - Clark, Tom C., Attorney General
  - Cleveland, Grover
  - Cleveland, Harlan
  - Cleveland Plain Dealer
  - Clise and Company, J. W.
  - Close, Upton, 2 folders
  - Clubb, O. Edmund
  - Cobb, Lee J.
  - Coblentz, E. D. [See: San Francisco, The Call Bulletin]
  - Codman, Mrs. Richard
  - Coe, Frank
  - Co-existence
  - Cohen, Benjamin
  - Cohen, Morris
  - Cohn, Roy M., 2 folders
    - Roy Cohn dinner, 1954 July 28; 5 discs
      Use copy reference number: 61002.10
    - Rest of folder not yet described
  - Colby, Bainbridge
  - Colby, Bainbridge (Box 36)
  - Cole, W. Sterling
  - Colegrove, Kenneth
  - Colegate University, 2 folders
  - College presidents, letters from
  - Colleges
  - Colliers Magazine
  - Colosimo, Tom
  - Columbia University, 2 folders
  - Combs, George Hamilton
    - Sound recording, 1952 May 20; 1 disc
      Use copy reference number: 61002.7
      Folder indicates "6 disks," only one disk present. However the folder also states "first hour," which is the contents of one disk (two sides). Extremely weak signal on disk.
    - Rest of the folder not yet described
  - Cominform meeting
  - Commager, Henry Steele, 2 folders
  - Commencement speech. "Available for commencement. Choice of three canned speeches...(by) Sole Proprietor of the China Lobby, Alfred Kohlberg,", 1956
  - Commentary (Box 37)
  - Commerce, U.S. Department of, 2 folders
  - Commissar of conservatives
  - Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy, 4 folders
  - Committee for a Free Asia, 4 folders
  - Committee for an Effective Congress
  - Committee for Collective Security
  - Committee for Constitutional Government, 1951-1958; 1 folder
  - Committee for Constitutional Government, 1951-1958; 6 folders (Box 38)
  - Committee for Cultural Freedom
  - Committee for Economic Development
  - Committee for Free Europe
  - Committee for Russian Relief
  - Committee for Non-Violent Action
  - Committee for World Development and World Disarmament
  - Committee of Fifteen
  - Committee of One Hundred
  - Committee of One Million [See also: Marvin Liebman], 1 folder
  - Committee of One Million, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Committee on Armed Services, Senate (82nd Congress)
    Includes letters sent to members of the House Committee on Armed Services.
  - Committee on National Affairs [See: Committee for an Effective Congress]
  - Committee on the Present Danger
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding Anti-Communist China
  - Committee to Proclaim Liberty
  - Common Cause
  - Common Sense
  - Commonweal, 2 folders
  - Commonwealth Club of California
    - Sound recording of speech, 1952 February 29; 1 disc
      Use copy reference number: 61002.3. A copy with better sound quality exists in the Commonwealth Club of California records, also available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
      Kohlberg talks about what he considers immoral actions on the part of the U.S. government including [his words] a "hypocritical" Atlantic Charter, the Cairo Agreement, deaths in Poland, and events in China and Korea. He believes that China was the scene of the greatest catastrophes suffered since World War II, and also the greatest breach of morals by the U.S. The U.S., he says, is paying the price of its Machiavellian immoralities to China on the battleground in Korea.
    - Rest of the folder is not yet described
  - Communes
  - Communism, facts on, from National Republic lettergrams (Box 40)
  - Communism, facts on, from the Congressional Record
  - Communism in China, 1927
  - Communist China, 2 folders
  - Communist immigrants from China
  - Communist international, 2 folders
  - Communist Manifesto
  - Communist party of China
  - Communist Party of the U.S.A.
  - Communist petitions
  - Communist research techniques [See: NTS]
  - Compass, The Daily, 4 folders
  - Comstock, Ada L.
  - Conant, James Bryant
  - Conant, Melvin A., Jr.
  - Condon, Edward V.
  - Condon, Robert L.
  - Conference of American Small Business Organizations
  - Conference of Asian Affairs, Inc.
  - Conference of Christians and Jews
  - Congress of American Women
  - Congress of Freedom (Box 41)
  - Congress of Racial Equality
  - Congress
  - Congressional Medal of Honor
  - Congressional Quarterly
  - Congressional Record, 2 folders
  - Congressmen, 2 folders
  - Congressmen, letters from, 2 folders
  - Conlon Associates, Ltd.
  - Connally, Tom, Committee on Foreign Relations, 3 folders
  - Connally Amendment
  - Conolly, Richard L.
  - Conrad, Arthur L., 2 folders
  - Conrad, Arthur L., National Physicians Committee, 3 folders (Box 42)
  - Conservative League
  - Consolidated - Vultee (a B-36 bomber)
  - Conspiracy
  - Constitution
  - Constitution of the Chinese Republic
  - Constitution of the Chinese Communist Party
  - Constitutional Educational League, Inc.
  - Contemporary China
  - Continuation Committee
  - Convergence
  - Cooke, Charles M., 4 folders
  - Coolidge, Charles A.
  - Coplon, Judith
  - Corbett, Harvey Wiley
  - Corson, Forrest E.
  - Couchiching Conference [See: Canadian Broadcasting Company] (Box 43)
  - Council Against Communist Aggression
  - Council Against Intolerance in America
  - Council for Judaism
  - Council of Jewish Federations and Welfare Funds
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 2 folders
  - Counter-Action
  - Counterattack
    - 1956-1960, 4 folders
    - 1949-1955, 7 folders (Box 44)
    - 1948-1950, 3 folders (Box 45)
  - Counts, George S.
  - Cousins, Norman
  - Cowen, Myron M.
  - Cowles, Gardner and John [See also: Look Magazine]
  - Crane, Burton
  - Crane, Henry Hitt
  - Crane, Jasper E.
  - Crankshaw, Edward, 2 folders
  - Cressey, George B.
  - Cripps, Sir Stafford
  - Crommelin, John G.
  - Cromwell, James H. R.
  - Cronback, Abraham
  - Cronin, Father John
  - Crouch, Paul
  - Crow, Carl (Box 46)
  - Crum, Bartley
  - Crusade for Freedom, 3 folders
  - Cuba (Cuban delegation to the United Nations)
  - Cuite, Thomas J.
  - Currency
  - Current History
  - Currie, Lauchlin
  - Curtice, Harlow
  - Curtis, Thomas B.
  - Cushing, Archbishop Richard J.
  - Cushman, Robert E.
  - Cvetic, Matt
  - Czechoslovakia
  - D, miscellaneous
    - 1959
    - 1958
    - 1956-1957
    - 1954-1955
    - 1953
    - 1951-1952
    - 1949-1950
    - 1947-1948
    - 1945-1946
    - 1944-1951
    - 1945-1950
  - Dahlberg, Edwin T.
  - Daily Worker and Sunday
    - 1950 April - 1955, 6 folders (Box 47)
    - 1947 November - 1949, 17 folders (Box 48)
    - 1946 June - 1947 October, 17 folders (Box 49)
    - 1945 December - 1946 May (Box 50)
    - 1944 - 1945 October, 6 folders (Box 51)
  - Dalai Lama
  - Dallas, George, 2 folders
  - Dallas News (Box 52)
  - Dallin, David J.
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, 2 folders
  - Davies, John P.
  - Davies, Raymond Arthur
  - Davis, Charles
  - Davis, Elmer
  - Davis, Jerome
  - Dean, Arthur H., 1944-1957; 5 folders
    - Sound recording, 1954 January 20; 1 disc
      Use copy reference number: 61002.9
    - Rest of folder not yet described
  - Dean, Vera Micheles (Box 53)
  - Decker, John W. [See also: International Missionary Council]
  - Declaration of Independence
  - Declaration of Washington
  - Defense, Department of
  - de Jaegher, Father Raymond
  - De Lacy, Hugh
  - Del Castillo, J. J.
  - Democratic Party platform, and Democratic National Committee members, 1948, 1952, 1956
  - Dennett, Raymond
  - Dennett, Tyler
  - Denver Post
  - Des Moines Register
  - Deutscher, Isaac
  - Development Loan Fund
  - De Voto, Bernard
  - Dewey, Thomas E., 3 folders
  - Dewey, Special Committee, 1948